this video I wanted to talk about how we
can have a peaceful voluntary revolution
which is a bit of an oxymoron because
the definition of a revolution is the
forcible overthrowing of your government
and I'm in no way talking about that but
there is no word for what I am talking
about because that is what historically
has been done in order to create a new
system you have to dismantle the current
one and that generally looks like
violent revolution but what we can do
together is create a parallel
cooperative system that people can
voluntarily opt into the analogy for
this and how we compete the current
system at competition how cooperation
can out peak out compete competition the
analogy for that is a tug of war game so
tug of war you have one team competing
on this side pulling the rope the other
team compete on this side pulling the
rope in this direction and whoever has
the most combined strength is going to
win time or game if on the competitive
side you have everyone pulling in
opposite directions everyone pulling in
their own direction it's not going to be
that hard for the unified side to pull
it with any amount of strength in one
unified direction and win this
tug-of-war game throw them off balance
and win the tug-of-war game how we do
that is by looking for that unified
direction allow them to be divided and
find the unification so that means I
don't get to dictate what anybody else
is like life looks like I only get to
meet you where you're at so I can find
out what my best diet is and I can move
towards it I can work on solutions that
are going to bring down my true cost of
food or keep my costs the same and
improve my diet on my own terms it
doesn't matter if you're keto or you're
vegan or your whole thirty you get to be
part of creating a solution that helps
you eat better
less and less resources your actual
resources the world's actual resources
we can combine forces to be able to
understand what is currently out there
without us need to recreate it reinvent
anything just inventing the thing that
helps us understand what is currently
happening in food in energy in
connection when a new idea comes out
there how do we know that it's how it
compares to what's already out there the
current system is marketing which is
pulling in every different direction
we're the best
they're not gonna what is the actual
number one coffeehouse well depends what
you mean by number one do you mean the
darkest the lightest the most caffeine
the hottest the freshest what is your
definition I want all of the above I
want the freshest medium roast ethical
coffee that would be if I needed
everyone to drink that that is not a
unified direction if instead it's like
okay I want everyone to be able to have
a cup of coffee and I want it to have
the least impact on the planet on the
people growing it I want to have the
least impact negative way and the most
impact in a positive way we can we can
agree on what direction to pull that by
looking at what unifies us instead of
what divides us and then any amount of
force in this direction wins and where
this analogy falls apart in the most
beautiful way is that you don't need to
let go of your rope on the competitive
side in order to join the cooperative
side so you can be on this side pulling
in your own direction running your
business being employed by one of the
other companies running a business and
to put you know food on the table and a
roof over your head and one hour a week
one hour a month ten dollars a month you
can pull in the unified direction for
all of humanity for yourself as well you
don't have to stop looking out for you
in order to be on this side you just
need to give a fraction of what the
energy are giving on this side in a
fractured way towards the energy in this
side in a unified way and together we
can create a world of abundance and
peace for everyone by out competing the
current
petition with cooperation thank you